[Road to Success]
[찬여번성: 별처럼 빛나리]
[Episode 9]
[제9화]
Oh, it's really...
진짜...
Stop with this sarcastic tone,
계속 그렇게 비꼬면
or I'll kick you out of here.
쫓아낼 줄 알아
Let me ask you a question.
하나만 물어보자
Did you sleep at her place last night?
너 어제 그 여자 집에서 잤지?
Did you not change your clothes
옷도 안 갈아입고
or take a bath? There's no bathtub at her place.
샤워도 안 했는데 그 집엔 욕조도 없잖아
Why are you giving me that look?
왜 그렇게 쳐다보는 건데?
Let's discuss an academic issue.
학술적인 문제에 대해 토론해 보자
How did she get so good?
그 여자가 어떻게 그렇게 대단할 수가 있어?
She's even better than a British doctor.
영국 의사보다 더 하잖아
She uses aromatherapy.
아로마겠지
Aromatherapy...
아로마?
Impressive.
대단하네
Speak your mind.
할 말 있으면 시원하게 해
What exactly are you up to?
뭐 어쩌자는 거야?
Why do have to be so dull?
왜 이렇게 무미건조해?
Alright.
알았어
Let's talk business.
본론으로 들어갈게
How's your investigation on the likelihood
린완싱이랑 스페이드 Q
of Lin Wanxing being Spade Q?
일치율은 어떻게 됐어?
They're 80% likely the same person.
80% 정도 돼
Eighty percent?
80%라고?
That's basically a positive match.
그럼 거의 확실한 거네
Not necessarily.
꼭 그렇지만은 않아
Something's odd about you.
너 좀 이상하다
You find her suspicious,
또 걔를 의심하면서도
yet you speak for her.
네 용의자를 의심하는구나
Interesting.
재밌네
That's quite a nice watch of yours.
그 시계 예쁘다
But I think it's mine.
내 것 같은데
I borrowed it
그날
along with the suit that day.
수트 빌릴 때 같이 빌렸잖아
You know I work at your sister's company.
내가 네 누나 회사에 다니는 거 알잖아
I must have a decent image.
내가 폼 좀 나야
I can't let anyone look down on you, can I?
남들이 널 무시하지 않을 거 아냐
Speaking of which,
말이 나와서 말인데
look at this watch
이 시계랑
and my outfit today.
오늘 내 스타일
How is it? I can make a good brother-in-law for you, right?
어때? 네 매형 같지?
Come on,
어서
call me that now.
날 제대로 불러 봐
I need to go for a morning run.
나 아침 조깅 가야 하니까
You stay here
넌 여기서
and dream on it.
계속 꿈이나 꾸고 있어
What do you mean by "dream on it"?
뭐가 꿈이란 거야?
How very rude.
버릇없는 놈
Ms. Lin.
린 선생님
-Coach. -Ms. Lin.
- 코치님 - 린 선생님
Ms. Lin.
린 선생님
Coach.
코치님
-Coach. -Hello, Ms. Lin.
- 코치님 - 린 선생님, 안녕하세요
-Is everyone here?
- 린 선생님 안녕하세요 - 다 모인 거지?
Today's training will be a bit different from usual.
오늘 훈련은 평소와 좀 다를 거야
Ms. Lin got you
너희 린 선생님이
a professional-level class on tactics.
너희를 위해 프로 전술 커리큘럼을 마련해 주셨거든
You mean a lesson for pros?
프로팀 수준 커리큘럼을요?
Yes.
그래
But forcing a lecture about professional tactics
하지만 지금 너희한테 억지로
on you right now is equal to
프로 전술을 가르치는 건
having you learn to run before you can walk.
걷지도 못하는데 뛰는 것부터 배우는 격이라
You'll stumble.
넘어지게 될 거야
No, we won't.
아니에요
We won't, Coach. We can make it.
그럴 일 없어요, 코치님 저희 다 돼요
-Trust us. -Yeah, Coach.
- 저희를를 믿으세요 - 맞아요, 코치님
-No way. -We can make it.
- 안 돼 – 할 수 있어요
Nonetheless, next,
하지만 이제부터
I will give you a taste of success.
너희에게 성공적인 경험을 안겨 줄 거야
What counts as a taste of success?
어떤 성공적인 경험을요?
It's easy to understand.
금방 알게 될 거야
It'll count as a success
너희가 골을 넣으면
as long as you score a goal.
그게 성공적인 거니까
Alright.
그럼
Warm-up exercise, now.
워밍업부터 해
Assemble!
모여
Next, I'll instruct you on Tactic No. 1.
지금부터 전술 1을 가르쳐 줄 거야
Though it's basic,
아주 기본적이지만
it's still beyond
여전히
the capabilities of many of you.
너희 대부분의 능력 밖일 거야
Coach, what is Tactic No. 1?
코치님, 전술 1이 뭐예요?
The core of Tactic No. 1 lies in
전술 1의 핵심은
playing defense before offense.
수비 후 역습이야
Fu Xinshu,
푸신수
tell us about the advantages
이번 상대인 뤼징 팀에 대해 말해 봐
of Lyujing, our rival team.
그 팀의 장점이 뭔지
Known as "the Hyenas,"
뤼징은 하이에나라고도 불리는데
among all youth training teams, Lyujing is famous for being strong
유소년 팀 중에서 공격은 강하지만
in offense, but weak in defense.
수비는 약한 팀으로 유명해요
That's right.
맞아
So we'll fight their attacks with stillness.
그러니 대형을 무너뜨리지 말고 타이밍을 잡아야 해
Our defensive strategy this time
이번 우리 수비 전략은
is to constrict the rival team's attacking front,
상대의 공격 공간을 압박하는 거야
while seeking a chance to assume the offensive.
그런 다음 기회를 봐서 역습하는 거지
Lyujing is best at rhythm,
뤼징의 필살기는 템포지
not stamina.
체력이 아니라서
You must stall and exhaust
반드시 붙잡아 둬야 해
them.
태극권처럼 말이야
We'll resort to the 4-5-1 Formation in the upcoming match.
이번 시합은 4-5-1 전술로 갈 거야
Defense before counterattacks.
수비 후 역습이지
Fu Xinshu, Zhi Hui, and Zheng Ren usually serve
원래는 푸신수, 즈후이, 정런이
as midfield players.
미드필더를 맡았는데
Chen Jianghe,
천장허
I need you to retreat from the forward
네가 공격 위치에서 내려와
and play midfield.
미들 라인에서 버텨 줘
Got it.
네
The 4-5-1 Formation
4-5-1 포메이션은
requires all midfield players to coordinate closely in defense,
미드필더의 긴밀한 협력 수비가 필요하고
the forward to intersperse with agility,
공격수는 유연하게 침투해야 해
and the defenders to hold the defense line tight.
수비수는 수비 라인을 견고히 다지고
Qin Ao, since you'll be the only forward,
공격수는 친아오 한 명뿐이니까
the important task
역습할 때
of assuming offense will be on you alone.
전부 네가 감당해야 할 거야
Is that clear, boys?
다들 알아들었지?
Wait.
잠깐만요, 잠깐만요
How come I don't get it?
전 잘 이해가 안 돼요
What don't you understand?
아직도 이해가 안 돼?
The coach is looking out for you losers.
코치님이 너희 같은 오합지졸을 수습하시는 거잖아
Who are you calling "losers"?
누구더러 오합지졸이래?
Don't you think the coach wants to teach us something?
코치님도 가르치고 싶어도
He simply can't do that
너희가 워낙 답이 없어서
because there's no way to get the message across.
못 가르치는 거야
As for why that happens,
왜 가르쳐도 모르는지
try figuring it out yourselves.
잘 좀 생각해 봐
I'm off for warm-up exercise.
난 몸 풀러 갈 테니까
-Qin Ao! -Qin Ao.
- 친아오
His harsh words are true, though.
재수 없어도 틀린 말은 아니잖아
Ms. Lin fought really hard to get us
우리를 위해 린 선생님이 전술 커리큘럼을 마련하셨잖아
this lesson, right?
얼마나 힘든 일인데
Yeah, it's very expensive.
맞아, 엄청 비쌀 거야
Please don't waste any time.
시간 낭비하지 말자
That's right!
그래
To prove he's a clown,
저 녀석 코를 납작하게 해 주려면
I must practice hard.
열심히 연습해야 해
-Exactly. -Let's go!
- 맞아 - 가자
Warm-up exercise.
몸 풀자
Watch the spacing.
간격 유지해
Keep the formation.
대형 유지하고
Defenders, watch the distance between each other.
서로의 수비 간격에 신경 써
Spread out like a net!
그물망 수비를 형성하라고
Zhi Hui, Zheng Ren,
즈후이, 정런
watch the spacing between you two.
너희 둘, 간격 유지하라고
Eyes on the rope.
라인을 봐
Got it!
네
Always mind your teammates who have formed a defense line.
항상 수비 라인을 만드는 동료들을 신경 써
With Wen Chengye, a new player on the team,
원청예라는 새로운 피가 수혈되니까
the morale seems to have truly improved.
팀 분위기가 정말 많이 좋아진 것 같아요
I feel like he'll give us even more surprises.
앞으로 더 많은 놀라움을 줄 것 같네요
Nice shot!
나이스 패스
-This way. Here! -Shoot!
이쪽이야, 이쪽
Did someone just score?
골 들어갔죠?
For borrowing my cap once,
야구 모자 한 번 빌리는데
[Receive Money by QR Code]
[QR 코드 입금]
you owe me 5 yuan.
5위안이에요
You're welcome.
고마워요
Seems like he's detained by the teacher again.
또 선생님한테 붙잡혀서 남은 거 같아
His skills...
그 패스 말이야
have never been up to par.
매일 불합격이네
Yeah.
그러게
He's even bad at copying others' moves, bro.
베끼는 것도 못 하더라
Others go easy on him,
봐주는 거 같아도
but he never notices it.
틈을 전혀 안 주는 거 같아
Hey, Mom.
여보세요, 엄마
Xinshu,
신수
how have you been?
요즘 잘 지내니?
Grandma told me you started playing football again.
외할머니한테 들었는데 너 또 축구 시작했다며?
I'm doing great, Mom.
잘 지내요
I just had a training session with my pals this afternoon.
오늘 오후에도 훈련했는데
-Today, we continued to... -Xinshu,
- 오늘 계속 합을... - 신수
I'm having a minor surgery soon.
엄마가 요즘 작은 수술을 해야 하는데
Uncle Li is short of cash.
리 아저씨도 돈이 별로 없다고 해서
So I wonder if I can borrow some from you.
너한테 좀 빌리려고 연락했다
Mom, what surgery are you getting?
엄마, 무슨 수술인데요?
And when?
언제하세요?
You... How about I come see you right now?
제가 지금 가서 같이 있을게요
-Just give me... -No need.
- 위치... - 아니야
It's just a minor surgery.
그냥 작은 수술이라
The exact time isn't confirmed yet.
아직 정확한 날짜는 안 나왔어
It's being scheduled.
순서를 기다려야 하거든
Mom, make sure you take good care of yourself.
엄마, 몸조리 잘하셔야 해요
I'll transfer money to you in a bit.
돈은 제가 바로 보내 드릴게요
Good.
그래
Send me the time and location of your football game.
경기 시간이랑 장소 보내 주렴
I'll come watch you play.
엄마도 보러 갈게
Great, Mom.
네, 엄마
I'll send you the info now.
지금 바로 보내 드릴게요
Then, later, I will...
그리고 제가 이따가...
[You're transfering] [10,000 yuan]
[이체 금액: 1만 위안]
[You're transfering] [39,000 yuan]
[이체 금액: 3만 9천 위안]
[Recipient Name: Guan Minjie]
[수령인: 관민제]
[Recipient Account Name: Guan Minjie]
[예금주: 푸신수]
Mom,
엄마
I've transferred money to you.
돈 보내 드렸어요
I've also sent you the location of the match.
경기장 주소도 보내 드렸으니까
Don't forget to come watch me play.
시간 맞춰서 꼭 오셔야 해요
Fu, are you done there yet?
푸신수, 뭐 하고 있어?
Talking to your girlfriend or what?
너 연애하냐?
I'm coming!
갈게
Hurry!
빨리 와
Do you guys know what just happened?
얘들아, 대박 뉴스야
What?
왜?
What happened?
무슨 일인데?
My mom said she'd come watch me play!
우리 엄마가 경기 보러 오신대
-Really? -Is it true?
- 진짜?
-Yes, for real! -Then you must bring your A game!
- 그래 - 그럼 잘해야겠네
Sure thing!
당연하지
Are you done here?
뭐 하고 있어?
Boss has ordered
대장이 벌써 다
the fist-shaped meatballs for us. Come on.
세팅했대, 얼른 가자
-Let's go eat! -Let's go!
- 먹으러 가자 - 가자
How nice of Boss.
센스 있네
Everything I covered in today's class is key knowledge.
오늘 배운 거 다 중요한 내용이니까
Make sure you review it properly afterwards.
열심히 복습해
Why are the three of you standing while taking notes?
너희 셋은 왜 서서 베끼고 있니?
Miss, the words...
선생님, 이렇게 베끼면
seem clearer this way.
더 잘 보이거든요
Fine.
알았어
Finish it, and you'll be dismissed.
다 베끼고 쉬는 시간 가져
Okay, got it.
- 네
Hey, the three of you!
너희 셋...
Let me take over. Let me!
내가 찰게, 내가
Defense needed!
막아
The coach told you to shut down the opponent,
코치님이 상대편을 막으랬지
not to miss the ball entirely.
공도 못 건드리게 하라는 건 아니야
Just you wait.
거기 서
Is it just me or has Boss become completely different?
대장 성격이 변했나?
He doesn't argue with Wen Chengye anymore.
원청예한테 시비도 안 거네
He's afraid that Ms. Lin is too poor
린 선생님 주머니 사정이 안 좋으실까 봐 그런 거야
to afford a second lesson for us.
커리큘럼이 워낙 비싸니까
Serve!
여기에
Here!
패스해
I'll take this.
이걸로 할게요
This scarf is priced at 308 yuan.
그 스카프는 308위안입니다
Not a problem.
좋아요
Anything on my face?
내 얼굴에 뭐 묻었어요?
No.
아니요
I just...
그냥...
wanted to thank you.
고맙다고 말하고 싶어서요
For what?
뭐가요?
For changing
애들을 대하는
your attitude toward those brats.
태도를 바꿔 줘서 고맙다고요
Have you noticed
코치님이 애들한테
that you've smiled at them a lot more lately?
웃어 준 횟수가 점점 느는 거 몰라요?
Have I?
그래요?
Yes, you have.
네, 그럼요
If you don't believe it,
못 믿겠으면
I'll take photos of you tomorrow.
내일 찍어서 보여 줄까요?
You're so childish.
뭘 그렇게까지
Although I don't know
여기에 얼마나
how long you'll stay here,
더 있을진 모르겠지만
I still need to thank you for acknowledging them.
애들을 인정해 줘서 고마워요
It truly
그 부분이
means a lot.
정말 중요하거든요
But my recognition
내가 인정한다고
can't help them win the game.
경기에서 이기는 건 아니에요
Don't worry about that.
그건 걱정 말아요
These days,
요즘
they are clearly eager
애들이 알아서 훈련하려는 의지가
to ask for additional practice.
흘러 넘치니까요
If drive alone led to success every time,
의욕만으로 보답받을 수 있다면
this world
세상 사는 법이
would be much simpler.
훨씬 간단했겠죠
At least they're highly motivated now, right?
그래도 일단 의욕이 있는 게 어디예요?
Such passion is enough
의욕만으로
to help them
한 번 정도 이기는 건
win a game.
가능하지만
But to keep a winning streak,
계속 이기려면
it's far from enough.
한참 부족해요
Were you
코치님은
just born this preachy?
원래 그렇게 원론적인 말만 해요?
Ms. Lin,
린 선생님
I'm talking about the cruel reality of this world.
난 이 세상의 잔혹한 현실을 말하는 거예요
[Three weeks later]
[3주 후]
That hoity-toity young master wants to play cool.
그냥 멋있는 척하게
Just let him be.
놔둬
Still, I think we should play it safe and focus on
내 생각엔 우리가 그냥 안정적으로
defense before striking back.
수비 위주로 역습을 노리는 게 좋겠어
Look at the time.
지금이 몇 시인데
Why isn't the coach here yet?
코치님은 아직 안 오시는 거야?
We'll be late if he doesn't show up soon.
이러다 우리 다 늦겠다
You guys go without me.
먼저 출발해요
I'm running a bit late for something.
난 일이 좀 있어서 늦을 것 같네요
The coach isn't around now,
코치님은 안 오셨지만
but we've done much practice
우리가 전술 1...
-on Tactic No. 1. -Ms Lin,
- 린 선생님 - 많이 연습했잖아
you still can't reach the coach?
코치님한테 아직 연락 없어요?
He said he'd run a bit late for something.
일이 있어서 늦으신대
Let's set out now.
우리 먼저 출발하자
Okay.
네
We've arrived. Wake up, guys.
다 왔다, 다들 일어나
Really, I mean...
이거 진짜...
Coach Wang, where are you now?
왕 코치님, 어디예요?
We've arrived at the court.
우린 벌써 경기장에 도착했어요
Are you bailing on us due to some emergency?
갑자기 일이 생겨서 못 오는 거예요?
This had better not get dirty.
더러워지면 안 되는데
Fu,
푸신수
are you dating someone?
너 연애하냐?
Cut that nonsense.
무슨 소리야?
I bought this as a gift for my mom.
우리 엄마가 주신 선물이란 말이야
You should have said so earlier.
진즉 말하지
Well...
그...
Ms. Lin,
선생님
is the coach still coming, at this hour?
코치님이 오시긴 하는 거예요?
[Are you bailing on us due to some emergency?]
[갑자기 일이 생겨서 못 오는 거예요?]
The coach is probably held back by something.
코치님한테 무슨 일 생긴 건 아니죠?
What could be more important than this match?
지금 경기보다 중요한 게 뭐가 있다고
The clock is ticking.
시간 없으니까
Let's go in now.
우리끼리 먼저 들어가자
-Let's go.
- 네 - 가자
An iced Americano, please.
아이스 아메리카노 한 잔 주세요
[Coach Wang, where are you now?]
[왕 코치님, 어디예요?]
[We've arrived at the court]
[우린 벌써 경기장에 도착했어요]
[Are you bailing on us due to some emergency?]
[갑자기 일이 생겨서 못 오는 거예요?]
Your Americano.
주문하신 아메리카노 나왔습니다
Thanks.
감사합니다
You must remember the tactics
모두 명심해
we talked about before the match.
내가 지시했던 대로
Exploit the rival team's weaknesses.
상대 약점을 파고들어서
Play it safe and steady.
안정적으로
At last, win the game.
승리하는 거야
Can you do it?
할 수 있겠어?
-Yes!
- 할 수 있습니다
Lyujing!
뤼징
-We've got this!
- 파이팅
Ms. Lin,
린 선생님
is the coach still coming?
코치님은 오시긴 하세요?
Yeah, is he coming?
맞아요, 오시는 거예요?
Do you even need to ask?
그걸 꼭 물어봐야 아냐?
He has clearly bailed on us,
상황을 봐라
as the situation has spoken for itself.
바람맞힌 게 뻔하잖아
The match hasn't begun yet.
아직 경기 시작도 안 했으니까
Let's be patient and wait.
조금만 더 기다려 보자
Hello?
여보세요
Something came up. I can't make it to the site.
일이 있어서 못 갈 것 같아요
Is it the coach?
코치님 전화예요?
What's with him?
무슨 일이래요?
Give me a second.
잠깐만
What happened?
무슨 일인데요?
How are you not coming?
못 오는 거예요?
This is an important day.
오늘 진짜 중요한 날인데
How could you stand us up?
어떻게 약속을 어길 수가 있어요?
What about the players?
애들은 어떡하고요?
What about the match?
경기는 어떡해요?
Put them on the phone.
애들 바꿔 줘요
The coach wants a word with you.
코치님이 너희랑 통화하고 싶으시대
-Coach.
- 코치님
-Are you coming?
- 언제 오세요?
The match will begin in a bit.
곧 킥오프예요
You're backing out or what?
도망치시는 거예요?
I'm not going to the site.
안 갈 거야
I knew this would happen.
그럴 줄 알았어
Without you,
안 오시면
how do we deal with this?
저희는 어떡해요?
We can't play in this case, Coach.
저희끼리는 못 한다고요
So, are you chickening out?
그래서 도망이라도 가게?
How is that possible?
무슨 소리예요?
We'll definitely play this match.
이 경기는 무조건 뛰어야죠
We'd sooner finish the game than quit.
도망가더라도 뤼징이랑 붙고 나서 가야죠
-Yeah. We'll crush Lyujing. -We're going to defeat them.
- 맞아, 뤼징이랑 싸우자 - 저희가 부숴버릴 거예요
We'll surely play this match.
당연히 뛰어야죠
Good.
좋아
Then forget about me, and bear in mind
그럼 내 존재는 잊고
what you have to do in the first half.
전반전 임무만 잘 기억해
That is to stick to Tactic No. 1, defense before offense.
전술 1, 수비 후 역습이죠?
Coach, when should we assume the offensive?
코치님 저희는 언제 공격해요?
You'll know when the time comes.
때가 되면 알게 될 거야
Remind yourselves
명심해
of the first lesson I taught you.
내가 너희한테 가르쳐 준 첫 번째 수업을
-Defense before offense. -When to strike, Coach?
- 수비 후 역습 - 언제래?
What do you mean?
어쩌란 거야?
-What? -Coach?
- 아니... - 코치님
He just hung up.
끊었네
Hello?
여보세요
-Hello? -No way.
- 여보세요? - 아니...
What does this mean: "We'll know when the time comes"?
때가 되면 안다는 게 무슨 말이야?
Wasn't the first lesson about playing defense before offense?
첫 번째 수업이 수비 후 역습 아니었어?
Yeah.
맞아
Alright, whatever.
됐어, 신경 쓰지 말고
Let's just do as the coach said.
코치님 말씀대로 하자
Have some faith in the coach.
코치님을 믿어 보자
Let's warm up.
몸 풀자
We don't have a coach again.
또 코치님 없이 뛰네
Those with no coach are always looked down upon.
코치가 빠지면 무시당할 텐데
Come on, guys.
이리 와
Huddle now.
어서
Come on!
손 내밀어
Ms. Lin.
린 선생님
Hongjing No. 8 High School!
훙징 제8고
-We've got this!
- 파이팅
-Alright. -Let's go!
- 좋아 - 가자
Go!
가자
Today, Lyujing International School
오늘 맞붙는 두 팀은
is playing Hongjing No. 8 High School.
뤼징 국제고등학교와 훙징 제8고등학교입니다
The former is known for its lightning-fast attacks,
뤼징 국제고는 번개 같은 속공으로 유명한 반면
while the latter secured a tie
훙징 제8고는 지난 경기에서
with surprising long balls
예상치 못한 롱패스와
and successful offside trap breaks
오프사이드 트랩 돌파에 성공하며
in the previous match.
동점을 만들었는데요
An experienced team with great rhythm
노련한 경기 조율의 대가와
is here to play some new elites with unpredictable tactics.
예측불허 전술의 신예가 맞붙을 예정이며
A clash of speed and wisdom is about to unfold.
스피드와 지혜의 격돌이 곧 펼쳐지겠습니다
The game starts now.
킥오프가 시작되겠습니다
The kickoff is taken
흰색 유니폼을 입은
by Jiang Tianyu in white, captain of Lyujing International.
뤼징 국제고 주장 장톈위 선수가 킥오프합니다
-You've got this! -Here!
- 파이팅 - 이쪽이야
Keeping possession of the ball well,
뤼징 국제고가 공을 확실히 점유하며
Lyujing International has launched a quick attack.
빠른 공격을 전개합니다
Defense! Defense!
막아, 막아
The left!
왼쪽으로
Pass the ball!
백 패스해
Lin Lu,
린루
didn't grow any taller lately, huh?
키가 그대로네
Jiang Tianyu has the ball now.
장톈위 선수가 공을 잡을 때
He's in the upper hand since he's taller.
신장에서 우위를 보이고 있습니다
He chooses to pass the ball to a midfield teammate.
중앙에 있는 동료에게 패스를 선택합니다
The players of Hongjing No. 8 High School
훙징 제8고 선수들이
are clearly setting up a solid defense.
수비에 굉장히 힘을 쏟고 있는 모습입니다
Liang!
량쯔
A chance for Hongjing No. 8 High School to attack!
훙징 제8고의 공격 기회입니다
Qin!
친아오
Go!
가자
Such an intense situation.
경기 상황이 매우 팽팽합니다
Lyujing International has been trying to attack,
뤼징 국제고는 계속해서 공격을 시도하지만
yet they're always intercepted by Hongjing at crucial moments.
결정적인 순간마다 훙징에게 공을 뺏기는군요
Compared to the previous match against Ning'an,
지난 닝안 팀과의 경기에 비해
Hongjing No. 8 High School has made
훙징 제8고가 확실히 전술 수행력과
noticeable improvement
결속력 면에서
in execution and cohesity.
크게 향상된 모습을 보여 줍니다
The core of Tactic No. 1 lies in playing defense before offense.
전술 1의 핵심은 수비 후 역습이야
Our defensive strategy this time
이번 우리 수비 전략은
is to constrict the rival team's attacking front,
상대의 공격 공간을 압박하는 거야
while seeking a chance to assume the offensive.
그런 다음 기회를 봐서 역습하는 거지
Defenders must watch the distance between each other
서로의 수비 간격을 유지하면서
and spread out like a net.
그물망 수비 라인을 형성해
Keep watch!
막아
The back! The back!
뒤에, 뒤에
-Good shot! -Fu!
- 나이스 - 푸신수
Bro,
야
seems like your skills are poor as ever.
네 축구 실력은 여전하네
On the field, Lin Lu
린루 선수가 경기장에서
and his former teammate Jiang Tianyu
옛 동료인 장톈위 선수와
are communicating on amiable terms.
다정한 대화를 나누고 있습니다
-Here! -Hongjing has put up an effective defense!
- 여기 - 훙징의 인상적인 수비로
Lyujing International hasn't scored a goal yet.
뤼징 국제고가 계속 득점을 못 하고 있지만
However, in the front, Hongjing only has
반대로 훙징 제8고는 공격 진영에
Qin Ao, number 9, as the forward.
9번 친아오 선수 하나뿐이라
Qin Ao is guarded by many
친아오 선수가 여러 명에게 마크를 당하면서
and has no chance to score.
득점 기회를 얻지 못하고 있습니다
Oh no, he lost the ball!
공을 뺏겼습니다
Qin Ao just hit the ground hard.
친아오 선수가 세게 넘어졌는데요
He staggered a bit when getting up to defend.
일어나서 수비로 복귀할 때 약간 비틀거립니다
Believe in yourselves.
자신을 믿으면
You'll win this.
너희 다 할 수 있어
One against many...
혼자서 여러 명을 상대하긴
This is too difficult.
너무 어려워
Lyujing is so overbearing.
뤼징 애들이 너무 거만해
They're way out of line.
진짜 너무하네
Why does he have to act cool?
뭘 잘났다고 이래?
The first half of the game
전반전 경기가
-is coming to an end. -Let me!
- 곧 끝나가는데요 - 내가 할게
Lyujing International launched multiple attacks.
뤼징 국제고는 여러 차례 공격을 시도하고 있지만
All Hongjing players just retreated for defense.
훙징 제8고의 전원 수비로
They're waiting for a chance.
기회만을 엿보고 있습니다
Seems like Hongjing has adopted the strategy
아무래도 오늘 훙징의 전략은
of playing defense before offense today.
수비 후 역습인 것 같습니다
That said,
하지만
the essence of this strategy is launching one decisive attack to secure victory.
수비 후 역습의 핵심은 한 방에 승부를 내는 것이죠
Let's see how they find the right moment.
과연 그 기회를 어떻게 살릴지 지켜보시죠
Still a coward, huh?
여전히 새가슴이네
You had no gut to attack though you had the ball.
슈팅 한 번을 못 때리니
You're like trash.
그러니까 쓰레기지
Soon you won't be this arrogant.
얼마나 잘난 척하나 두고 보자
You didn't show up
오지도 않고
or even leave an instruction.
말 한마디도 없고
How's that appropriate?
이게 말이 돼요?
Don't forget you are the coach.
당신이 코치잖아요
The first half is over.
전반전 경기가 종료되었습니다
Zero to Zero, a tie for the time being.
양 팀 0 대 0 무승부입니다
Have some water.
물 마셔
What did the coach say?
코치님이 뭐래요?
He hasn't replied yet.
아직 답장이 없어
Anyway, just keep your composure.
그냥 일단 너희 페이스대로 해
You played the first half well.
전반전 좋았잖아
"Well"?
좋긴 뭐가 좋아요?
It went terrible.
지금 뭐 하는지도 모르겠는데
We didn't even launch a decent attack.
제대로 된 공격 한 번 못 했어요
It's true that we defended all the attacks,
우리가 공은 다 막았지만
but the pressure on the backcourt players was too heavy.
후방 수비진 부담이
We couldn't keep up physically,
너무 크니까
since we were on the back foot the entire time.
체력이 못 따라주고 있어요
I alone simply can't break through a group of people.
저 혼자서는 여러 명을 뚫을 수도 없다고요
What is it called?
적어도
"One cannot tango."
한 손으로는 아무 소리도 안 난다고요
Boss,
대장
the correct saying is "it takes two to tango."
그건 손바닥을 마주쳐야 소리가 난다고 말해
You know what I mean.
비슷한 뜻이잖아
Pool your strength together.
화력을 집중하면
I believe you can win this. Just go for it.
너희는 할 수 있을 거야
Yeah.
그래
Qin Ao is the only forward anyway.
어차피 친아오 한 명뿐인데
All the strength is there already.
화력은 집중되잖아
No matter what, backcourt players
어쨌든
just focus on passing the ball.
후방에서 패스 많이 돌리고
Catch every window to pass it to the front court.
공간 나면 바로 전방으로 보내
Is passing the ball to you of any help?
너한테 줘서 뭐 하게?
Idiot.
어차피 날리면서
Better than passing it to you, right, bro?
너한테 주는 것보단 낫잖아
Let's put in more effort in the second half.
후반전에 좀 더 힘내 보자
We'll try our best, guys!
다들 힘내
-Seek a chance to strike back. -We've got this!
- 반격할 기회는 있어 - 파이팅
An iced Americano, thanks.
아이스 아메리카노 주세요
Did you come here for a business meeting?
사업하러 왔어?
A bid conference will commence here in half an hour.
30분 뒤에 여기서 계 모임이 있거든
I heard you were around,
네가 여기 있다길래
so I came see you.
얼굴이나 보러 온 거야
Just the same as ever.
여전하네
Someone's using me to gain favors with others again.
누가 또 날 팔아서 생색냈나 했지
Having value means being needed.
가치가 있다는 건 필요하다는 뜻이야
It's a good thing.
좋은 거잖아
There is a word carved on my forehead–
내 이마에는 이런 단어가 새겨져 있어
"priceless."
무 가치
Now I finally see
드디어 너한테서
Dad's genes at play in you.
아빠의 유전자가 빛을 발하는 게 보인다
Your players are having a fierce game,
네 선수들은 열정적으로 뛰고 있는데
while you are sitting here drinking coffee.
넌 여기서 커피나 마시고 있고
Seems like they don't hold much value in your heart.
네 마음속에서 선수들 가치가 별로 높지 않은가 봐?
You're overthinking it.
그건 오해야
I simply think that as Hongjing's interim coach,
난 그냥 훙징의 임시 코치로서
there's no need to create
애들한테 굳이
the false impression that I'll stay for the long haul,
내가 오래 맡을 거라는 착각을 안 주려고 그러거든
and hence upset them when we part ways.
헤어질 때 괜히 마음만 아프니까
Besides, Lyujing isn't that good.
그리고 뤼징이 그렇게 강하지도 않아서
Hongjing can handle them.
애들이 알아서 잘할 거야
My dear brother,
왕파
you love this football team.
너 훙징 팀을 좋아하는구나
No, I'm just testing my abilities.
내 능력을 시험하는 중이야
That's an excuse.
변명하지 마
Don't you think I know you well?
내가 널 모를까 봐?
You've grown fond of this two-bit football team over time.
저런 삼류 팀에 정든 거잖아
I'm just curious.
근데 왜 하필
Why would you pick it?
저런 팀을 고른 거야?
You never act on impulse.
넌 그렇게 감정적으로 움직이지 않잖아
The point is,
중요한 건
this team is really bad.
저 팀은 너무 형편없어서
It shouldn't have caught your eye.
네 눈에 찰 리가 없다는 거야
So?
그래서?
So, this team is not your target.
그래서 네가 팀 때문에 온 건 아니라고 봐
I've asked Yu Bo.
위보한테 물어봤는데
He wouldn't tell.
대답해 주진 않지만
But I already have a rough idea.
대충 짐작은 가
The second half is about to begin.
곧 후반전 시작이야
I don't have time to chat with you.
누나랑 잡담할 시간 없어
I hope you know what you're doing
네가 정말 잘 알고 있길 바라
and never waste your ability
네 능력을
on pointless causes.
쓸데없는 곳에 낭비하지 말고
Ji,
지 기사
I'm done here.
여기 볼일 끝났으니까
Bring the car around.
차 시동 걸어
[The second half]
[후반전]
The second half begins.
후반전 경기가 시작됐습니다
Run! Run!
달려, 달려
Put up a defense!
막아, 막아
Lyujing players are encouraging each other to attack.
계속해서 팀원들의 공격을 이끌고 있습니다
Yes, pass it along!
그래, 전진 패스해
-Pass the ball along! -Pass the ball!
- 빨리 안으로 패스해 - 패스
We can tell that Lyujing International's attacks in the second half
후반전에 뤼징 국제고의 공격이
are much fiercer.
더욱 거세진 것을 느낄 수 있습니다
-Run faster! -But this will expose
- 이는 뤼징의 수비가 - 빨리 달려
an obvious loophole in their defense.
헐거워졌단 뜻이기도 합니다
For Hongjing No. 8 High School,
훙징 제8고에게는
it's a good opportunity to counterattack,
역습의 좋은 기회죠
provided
하지만 그전에
that they withstand such an onslaught.
거센 공세부터 막아내야 합니다
Good shot!
슈팅 좋았어
Bravo!
잘했어
Time for a corner kick.
코너킥이야
Come on, put up a defense!
수비해
They're playing at too fast a pace.
쟤들 템포가 너무 빨라
Just a stamina test, isn't it?
체력 싸움 하자는 거야
I can match up.
견딜 수 있어
Don't get carried away.
흥분하지 마
Remind yourself of what the coach said.
코치님이 뭐라고 하셨는지 잊지 말고
Lyujing is best at rhythm,
뤼징의 필살기는 템포지
not stamina.
체력이 아니라서
You must stall and exhaust
반드시 붙잡아 둬야 해
them.
태극권처럼 말이야
"Exhaust them."
그놈의 태극권
But it'll kill me not to strike now.
더 참다간 숨 막혀 죽겠다
Just try to hold steady.
진정해
Lyujing International just won a corner kick in the front court.
뤼징 국제고가 전방에서 코너킥 기회를 얻었습니다
It will be taken by Player No. 4.
4번 선수가 찹니다
Get the defense set up well!
잘 막아
Let's see his choice for this corner kick.
이번 코너킥을 어떻게 처리할지 지켜보시죠
The ball went for the goal
골문 앞으로 공을 띄웠습니다
and was pushed away by Hongjing's goalkeeper with one hand,
훙징 제8고 골키퍼가 한 손으로 쳐낸 뒤
which earned the team a chance to attack.
팀이 공격 기회를 잡았습니다
They chose to bring the ball to the left flank.
일단 왼쪽으로 공을 보냅니다
Both teams are fighting fiercely for the ball now.
양 팀 모두 발밑 싸움이 아주 치열한데요
-The ball! -Pass!
- 공 줘 - 패스
-Lin Lu!
- 린루
-Go check on him!
- 어서 가 봐
-A player got hurt and fell on defense. -Lin Lu!
- 수비 상황에서 부상인가요? - 린루
Lin Lu, are you okay?
린루, 괜찮아?
-Are you having a cramp?
- 쥐난 거 아니야?
Lu,
린루
-are you okay? -What happened?
- 괜찮아? - 왜 그래?
Don't move. Lie still.
움직이지 마
-Can you move your leg? Must be a cramp. -Take a deep breath.
- 다리 움직일 수 있어? - 쥐가 난 거야
Listen, raise your leg.
다리 높이 들어 봐
-Don't fret, guys. -How is Lin Lu?
- 흥분하지 말고 - 린루, 어때?
-I'll give you a spray and then a massage. -Lin Lu!
- 약 뿌리고 마사지 해 줄게 - 린루
-Don't move. Don't move. -Just position your leg right.
- 움직이지마 - 자세 바로 해
Don't move.
함부로 움직이지 마
Later on, target Player No. 6.
이따 6번 쪽으로 공격해
He can't hold on much longer.
쟤 거의 갈렸어
Come here, guys!
다들 모여
No pressure, fellows.
편하게 볼 돌려
Come huddle!
자리 잡자
-Relax. Nice and slow. -This is it.
- 천천히 움직여 봐 - 그래
Relax. Just relax.
힘 빼, 힘 빼
They're definitely going to overload on Lin Lu's side.
이제 쟤네 분명 린루 쪽으로 파고들 거야
I'll try to cover for him.
내가 어떻게든 커버해 볼게
But in this case...
그럼
will we stand a chance of scoring?
골은 누가 넣어?
Forget about the 4-5-1 Formation.
무슨 놈의 4-5-1이야
We might as well all play defense.
그냥 전원 수비로 내려앉자
"Well"?
좋긴 뭐가 좋아요?
It went terrible.
지금 뭐 하는지도 모르겠는데
We didn't even launch a decent attack.
제대로 된 공격 한 번 못 했어요
What is it called?
적어도
"One cannot tango."
한 손으로는 아무 소리도 안 난다고요
Boss, the correct saying is "it takes two to tango."
그건 손바닥을 마주쳐야 소리가 난다고 말해
Pool your strength together.
화력을 집중하면
I believe you can win this. Just go for it.
너희는 할 수 있을 거야
Qin Ao is the only forward anyway.
어차피 친아오 한 명뿐인데
All the strength is there already.
화력은 집중되잖아
Coach, when should we assume the offensive?
코치님 저희는 언제 공격해요?
You will know when the time comes.
때가 되면 알게 될 거야
Remind yourselves
명심해
of the first lesson I taught you.
내가 너희한테 가르쳐 준 첫 번째 수업을
Blind obedience makes people numb.
맹목적인 복종은 사람을 무감각하게 만들어
On the field,
경기장에서
if players only follow orders
선수가 지시만 받고
without using their brains,
스스로 생각하지 않으면
that's a crime.
범죄나 다름없는 거야
The first lesson Coach taught us was not playing defense before offense,
코치님이 가르쳐 준 첫 수업은 수비 후 역습이 아니었어
nor the 4-5-1 Formation.
4-5-1도 아니었고
It was that we must use our brains
경기를 이해하라는 거야
when we play football.
머리로 축구하라는 거라고
Then what should we do?
그럼 이제 뭘 어떡해?
We need another forward besides you.
너 혼자 공격하는 건 힘드니까
Let's make it two.
둘이 움직여
I'll take that role.
내가 할게
That's more like it.
그래
Two on two. That's only fair.
2 대 2로 싸워야 공평하지
Today, I let you boys take full charge of the match
오늘 경기장은 완전히 너희한테 맡길 거야
because I believe
내가 없어도
that even if I'm not on the site,
너희가 여전히
you can still stay clear-headed
냉정함을 유지하고 경기를 이해해야
and use your brains
이길 수 있다는 걸
to win the game.
믿기 때문이지
You've got this!
- 파이팅
-Go for it! -Well done!
- 잘했어
The formation's different now.
포메이션이 바뀌었다
Defense! Defense! Quick!
수비 복귀해, 빨리
Good job.
잘했어
-Defense! -The primary issue isn't the formation,
- 너희는 포메이션 문제보다 - 수비 복귀해
-but thinking. -Pass it over!
- 경기 이해력이 문제야 – 패스해
Cut through them!
중간으로 파고들어서
Steady the defense line!
수비 라인 안정시켜 줘
Congratulations, boys.
축하한다
You've finally seen the whole picture.
드디어 바둑판 전체를 보게 됐구나
The 4-4-2 Formation
바로 4-4-2가
is the correct approach for the second half.
후반전의 정답이었거든
In the second half, Hongjing seems to have
후반전 훙징 제8고는
adopted a different approach
팀의 포메이션을 바꾼 것 같습니다
and changed from the 4-5-1 Formation to the 4-4-2 Formation.
4-5-1에서 4-4-2로 변경했습니다
Such an alteration
포메이션을 바꾼 후에
has opened some opportunities or them to attack.
공격 기회도 좀 잡고 있네요
-Get a move on. Put up a defense! -No more dawdling.
- 어서 수비 복귀해 - 서 있지 마
-P-Put up a defense! -Defense!
- 복귀해 - 수비 복귀해
No need to rush.
서두르지 마
You will eventually score a goal.
골문은 조만간 너희 것이 될 거야
Come back here! Come!
돌아와, 돌아와
Coach.
코치님
They've changed to the 4-4-2 Formation.
쟤네가 4-4-2로 바꿨어
Watch our defense line.
수비 신경 쓰고
Pick up the pace on offense.
공격 속도 올려
Got it, Coach.
네, 코치님
Have both forwards suppress their center-backs,
투톱으로 상대 센터백을 압박해
and never let Lyujing easily break through the defense.
뤼징이 쉽게 수비를 뚫지 못하게 하고
What you need to do
너희가 해야 할 일은
is push Lyujing further
뤼징을 더 몰아붙여서
till weak spots show in their defense.
수비 라인에 빈틈을 만드는 거야
Hongjing, Hongjing!
- 훙징
When you take control of the pace,
템포를 너희가 장악하면
Lyujing's attacks will start to appear
뤼징의 공격은
impatient and repetitive.
조급하고 단조로워지게 될 거야
Their formation will be gradually compressed
상대 포메이션은 점점 압박을 받아서
and turn like a stretched rubber band
팽팽하게 당겨진 고무줄처럼
that could break anytime.
언제든 끊어질 수 있어
Hold the line!
막아, 막아
Faster!
더 빨리
Nice shot!
슈팅 좋았어
-Go for it! -You've got this!
파이팅, 파이팅
That was a pity.
아깝네
Fu!
푸신수
Jiang Tianyu, captain of Lyujing,
뤼징의 주장 장톈위 선수가
knocked down Fu Xinshu, captain of Hongjing!
훙징의 주장 푸신수 선수를 넘어뜨렸습니다
-Let's see what the referee calls. -Fu!
- 심판이 어떻게 판정할까요? - 푸신수
Are you okay, Fu?
괜찮아, 푸신수?
Fu!
푸신수
Are you okay?
괜찮아?
-Fu. -Mind your movements.
- 푸신수 - 경고입니다
-Are you alright, Fu? -I’m fine.
- 괜찮아, 푸신수? - 괜찮아
Jiang, did you do that on purpose, didn't you?
너 일부러 그랬지?
Fight me, I dare you!
어디 한판 붙어 볼래?
What does this mean?
뭐 하자는 거야?
Back to the game.
경기 속행합니다
Up for a fight, aren't you?
한번 붙어 보자는 거야?
Don't get physical!
싸우지 마, 싸우지 마
Just don't start a fight.
싸우지 마
Fu,
푸신수
-how are you holding up? -I'm doing okay.
- 괜찮아? - 괜찮아
This is infuriating.
진짜 열 받네
All's fine now.
괜찮아
The referee gave Jiang Tianyu, captain
주심이 뤼징 국제고의
of Lyujing International, a yellow card as a warning.
장톈위 선수에게 옐로카드를 줬고
Hongjing No. 8 High School
훙징 제8고는
has been awarded a set piece,
세트피스 기회를 얻었습니다
which will be taken by Fu Xinshu.
푸신수 선수가 킥을 준비합니다
But given that their both forwards
하지만 훙징의 두 공격수는
are being heavily guarded by Lyujing International,
뤼징의 집중 마크를 받고 있는데요
Hongjing's best passing lane has been cut off.
최적의 패스 루트가 차단돼서
Right now,
이제 모든 부담이
all the pressure
전부
is on Fu Xinshu.
푸신수 선수에게 쏠렸습니다
-Here! -Will he find that one only crack?
- 여기야 - 과연 해결책을 찾을까요?
Coach!
코치님
May I ask you a question?
여쭤볼 게 하나 있어요
Well,
그러니까
what's the most important job for a captain?
주장에게 가장 중요한 게 뭔가요?
It is to trust your teammates.
팀원들을 믿으면 돼
I-Is it that simple?
그렇게 간단한 건가요?
It is your teammates' trust in you
네가 주장인 건
that makes you their captain.
팀원들이 널 믿기 때문이야
At critical moments,
그리고 결정적인 순간에
trusting your teammates
네가 팀원들을 믿는 것이
matters more than anything else.
가장 중요해
A captain has to see
주장은
the potential in every teammate.
팀원들의 가능성을 볼 줄 알아야 하거든
Wen Chengye!
원청예
Fu Xinshu passed the ball to Player No. 11, Wen Chengye.
푸신수 선수가 11번 원청예 선수에게 패스합니다
The latter caught the ball with his chest.
원청예 선수가 가슴으로 공을 받아 냅니다
Destroy their defense!
밀고 들어가
Jiang Tianyu tried to turn the tables with a slide tackle.
장톈위 선수가 태클로 막아보려 하지만
But Wen Chengye
바로
pulled the ball back
원청예 선수가 드래그백으로
and easily moved it around Jiang Tianyu.
가볍게 장톈위를 제칩니다
[Hongjing No. 8 High School Football Team]
[훙징 제8고등학교 축구팀]
Wen Chengye passed the ball to Player No. 7, Chen Jianghe.
원청예 선수가 7번 천장허에게 패스합니다
The ball paused and went right for the goal.
공을 트래핑한 뒤 골문 앞으로 크로스
Player No. 9 Qin Ao headed the ball.
9번 친아오의 헤딩입니다
Goal!
골
A superb piece of teamwork!
환상적인 호흡입니다
One to zero!
1 대 0입니다
When you have faith in yourselves,
너희 자신을 믿으면
you will win.
이길 수 있어
♪ No matter how long the road ahead ♪
♪ 미래가 멀다 해도 ♪
Time's up. The game is over.
시간 종료, 경기가 끝났습니다
♪ Nothing can stop me ♪
♪ 내 질주는 멈추지 않아 ♪
Congratulations to Hongjing No. 8 High School
훙징 제8고등학교의
for winning the game with a score of one to zero,
1 대 0 승리를 축하합니다
♪ Break through every haze of doubt ♪
♪ 모든 방황을 부수며 ♪
remaining undefeated in the first two matches.
이로써 앞선 두 경기까지 무패 행진을 이어갑니다
♪ Chase the light within me ♪
♪ 나만의 빛을 쫓아가 ♪
♪ Strong wings grow through the storm ♪
♪ 풍파 속에서 끝내 강인한 날개를 펼칠 테니까 ♪
♪ Even if no one cheers ♪
♪ 모두가 날 외면해도 ♪
♪ I'll keep fighting my way through ♪
♪ 힘을 다해 싸울 거야 ♪
♪ On a deserted battlefield ♪
♪ 아무도 없는 경기장에서 ♪
♪ I grow stronger with a resounding voice ♪
♪ 당당하게 성장해 ♪
♪ I'll take every scar ♪
♪ 모든 상처를 ♪
♪ As my badge of honor ♪
♪ 영광의 훈장으로 삼을 거야 ♪
♪ If facing every storm is ♪
♪ 거센 풍파를 용감하게 마주하는 것만이 ♪
♪ What it takes to grow ♪
♪ 성장이라고 한다면 ♪
Coach, I can't believe you hid somewhere intentionally.
코치님 일부러 숨어 계셨어요?
♪ I will stubbornly go against the current ♪
♪ 난 기꺼이 그곳에서 ♪
[South Grandstand Entrance 1]
[남쪽 관람석 1번 게이트]
That was way out of line.
너무하시네요
What do you think?
어땠어요?
♪ And let myself go wild ♪
♪ 뜨겁게 싸워 볼 거야 ♪
A nice kick, wasn't it?
제 킥 괜찮았죠?
Coach, I'm telling you,
코치님
that winning goal was amazing.
그 결승 골은 진짜 멋졌죠?
-What did you have to do with it? -No, Boss...
- 그게 너랑 무슨 상관이야? - 대장
I put up a great defense with a kick.
내가 수비를 잘해서 그런 거야
Listen, listen.
내 말 들어 봐
[Mom]
[엄마]
This was a real eye-opener.
이번에 아주 눈이 번쩍 뜨이더라
[Call History]
[통화 기록]
You've got a lot to learn.
너도 좀 배워
-Bro... -I completely nailed the game.
내가 아주 박살을 냈다고
He's lost all his dignity after that stupid transfer.
그깟 학교로 전학 가 봤자 별거 없어
[South Grandstand Entrance 1]
[남쪽 관람석 1번 게이트]
The transfer left him no choice but...
걔는 안 돼 그 학교로 전학 가도...
Here comes the bus.
- 차 왔다
-Let's go. -Fu Xinshu,
- 푸신수 - 가자
-anything wrong? -Let's go.
- 왜 그러니?
Ms. Lin,
린 선생님
my mom promised to come watch my game,
엄마가 제 경기를 보러 온다고 하셨는데
but she didn't show up.
안 오셨어요
Have you reached her yet?
연락 안 되니?
I called her many times but couldn't get through.
제가 몇 번이나 전화했는데 안 받으세요
She mentioned before that she felt unwell
일전에 몸이 안 좋다고 하셔서
and needed surgery.
수술한다고 하셨거든요
Could something have happened to her?
무슨 일 생기신 건 아니겠죠?
Don't fret.
너무 걱정 마
Ms. Lin,
린 선생님
has something really happened to her?
정말 무슨 일 생긴 건 아니겠죠?
Calm down. Calm down.
너무 흥분하지 마
How about I go with you to find her?
나도 같이 찾아볼게
I don't know where she is.
엄마가 어디 계신지도 모르는걸요
Let's head to your home first.
그럼 네 집에 먼저 가 보자
If things get tough...
정 안 되면...
Then I'll figure out a solution.
내가 어떻게든 찾아봐 줄게
I'll go with you.
같이 가요
W-We will go with you too.
저희도 같이 갈게요
No.
안 돼
Too many cooks spoil the broth.
사람 많으면 방해만 돼
You guys wait at the hotel.
너희는 일단 호텔에서 기다려
I'll keep you updated if anything comes up.
무슨 일 생기면 바로 알려 줄게
Okay. Off you go then.
그럼 어서 가자
Don't worry.
진정해
I'll call a cab and take you to find her now.
지금 택시 잡아서 같이 찾아보자
Let's go.
어서
Hey, are you leaving with them or...
학생은 버스 안 탈 거니?
Sir, no need to wait for him.
기사님, 쟤는 놔두고 가요
The young lord here only rides in his designated car.
도련님은 전용차를 타셔야 한대요
Let's go!
어서 가요
Drive, sir.
가요, 기사님
We can set out now.
가시죠
You can drive now, sir.
출발해 주세요, 기사님
Sir, I'll scan the Wechat payment code. How much?
기사님, QR로 얼마 드리면 돼요?
I have cash on me.
나 현금 있어요
You have cash?
현금 있어요?
[The Royal Court]
[로열 하우스]
What are you doing? Come back here!
뭐야? 거기 서
Fu Xinshu!
푸신수
-Fu Xinshu! -Hold on!
- 푸신수 - 잠시만요
Even in a rush, you must register first.
아무리 급해도 등록은 해야죠
Your IDs, please.
신분증 주세요
Get upstairs now.
빨리 올라가자
This violin cost a large sum of money.
그 바이올린 비싸게 주고 산 거니까
You must study hard.
열심히 배워야 한다
-Got it. -Good boy.
- 알았어요 - 착하지
Mom,
엄마
who is he?
누구예요?
Get in here already.
얼른 들어와
Why the dawdling? Who are you talking to?
꾸물거리면서 누구랑 얘기해?
Someone's asking for directions. I'll be right with you!
누가 길 물어봐서 금방 갈게
Mom.
엄마
Why did you come here?
여긴 어떻게 왔니?
I couldn't reach you. I...
연락이 안 돼서요
You said you'd have surgery,
수술하신다고만 하고
but you didn't tell me when.
언제 하시는지 몰라서
I thought something happened to you, so I...
무슨 일 생긴 줄 알았어요
The hospital misdiagnosed.
병원에서 오진이었대
I'm actually well.
난 괜찮아
A-And the money for the surgery...
수술비는요?
I've spent it.
돈은 다 썼어
Your younger brother plays the violin well.
네 동생 바이올린 잘 켜잖니
Uncle Li had to get him a better one.
아저씨가 좋은 걸로 바꿔 줬어
Alright. If there's nothing else, off you go.
아무 일 없으니까 그만 가 보렴
Why did you lie to me?
왜 속이셨어요?
Every time
매번
you said you'd come see me,
저 보러 오겠다면서
it was just to get me to wire you money.
돈만 받아가셨잖아요
Why did you lie to me like that?
왜 자꾸 저를 속여요?
I didn't lie to you.
속인 거 아냐
I really don't have time today.
오늘은 정말 시간이 없었어
Besides, Uncle Li wouldn't let me go see you.
그리고 아저씨가 못 가게 해서 그래
Mom,
엄마
when will you ever have time to visit me?
언제쯤 시간 내서 절 보러 오실 거예요?
Enough, Xinshu.
그만하자, 신수
You're almost an adult.
너도 이제 다 컸잖니
Stop being so harsh on me, okay?
엄마한테 그만 징징대
What do you mean by being harsh on you?
제가 뭘 징징댔어요?
Mom, have I done anything wrong?
제가 뭘 잘못했나요?
You said you needed surgery.
수술하셔야 한다고 해서
So I gave you the entire sum of the money Grandpa left me
외할아버지가 돌아가시면서 저한테 남겨주신 돈을
when he passed away, Mom.
전부 다 드린 거예요
That was all I had.
제 전 재산이었다고요
But you...
근데 그걸로...
you spent it on a violin for that boy.
그걸로 쟤한테 바이올린을 사 주신 거예요?
Then what about me?
전 어떡하고요?
I did mess up on that issue.
돈 문제는 내가 잘못했다
Xinshu,
신수
can you try to understand me?
엄마 사정도 좀 이해해 주면 안 되겠니?
These years haven't been easy for me.
엄마도 그동안 쉽지 않았어
It's not that I don't want to see you.
널 만나기 싫어서가 아니야
But whenever I speak of you,
아저씨가 네 얘기만 꺼내면
Uncle Li gets mad,
자꾸 화만 내고
accusing me of neglecting the family
내가 집안일은 안 돌본다며
and threatening to divorce me.
나랑 이혼하겠다잖니
I have no option.
나도 어쩔 수가 없었어
I admit I've done you wrong.
엄마가 미안하다
Don't come find me again.
앞으로 다신 날 찾아오지 마라
-Fu Xinshu!
- 푸신수
Are you okay?
괜찮니?
Are you alright?
괜찮으세요?
-Sorry about that. -Thanks.
- 죄송합니다 - 고맙습니다
I admit I've done you wrong.
엄마가 미안하다
Don't come find me again.
앞으로 다신 날 찾아오지 마라
♪ There's nothing to fear ♪
♪ 두려울 게 없어 ♪
♪ Because you're with me ♪
♪ 네가 있으니까 ♪
♪ The light shimmers ♪
♪ 희미한 빛이 비쳐 ♪
♪ Brilliant as stars ♪
♪ 별처럼 찬란하게 빛나 ♪